Welcome back we're here live built twenty fifty this
...awesome conference and I'm excited to be with you guys you literally make the
house where in I live I love visual studio tell me a
little bit first about who you are what you do and what are some of the cool things coming out for
visual studio the next release so let's start over here mark so I'm
models and thomas and I work on the core visual studio id et I look
...to the...which is the place where...
imagine twelve that was a magic happens sometimes eighteen hours a day it's right so,
I live there and, I've been working on some productivity features and the
twenty fifteen cycle will maybe give you a little look at the moment...hall
...program manager on the diagnostics team...work on the debugging performance tools and visual studio
...of the...things we brought to visited two thousand fifteen include what
...continue improvements dice the ability to use lambdas...the watch window and debugging on
dot net and we brought some performance tools into the editor in into the
debugging tools as well so we can show you how long code text execute, for example,
just while you're stepping running to break points awesome...it was cooler I also work on the visit
...core teams our team at does the core parts of...for all languages
...editing in the building in...debugged
...as well so anything that release all languages what we
do lots awesome well we've got them here so please
ask some questions otherwise I'm just going to go crazy tell me about the
new stuff coming out why is exciting maybe even show us a little bit of what's going on
sure we do I think big thing for...five-fifteen isfocus on
...productivity so as always the...developers appreciate productivity and we have a lot of that the
...so stuff on the editor and
...going to be so some stuff on the blogger and there's lots of let's start with the editor because that's where
...all starts that's...we type it and then with your stuff that's we figure out what we type wrong that's what I start
...funny that you should mention it's about getting things wrong because my world this
...releases really been about the first stage of getting things wrong and how to avoid it right
...it's about...so, what
you see in my visual studio right now is I'm looking at a project that I've been working on I've
got an error present in the project you'll see I've got my error let's stop...the fairly typical
developer thing when I'm working thrillist...it's kinda like my to do this right so,
I...and sure enough I'm...go right to the lines of code as the
...that's nothing new it's been like that for a long-time but, you might notice if you're watching
...this move my mass overhear zoom in all as a
...new guy in town and that's the light bulb...left ok so, you notice...
he has a keyboard shortcut now I'm a guy who likes to keep my hand on the cable right okay so what I'm going
to do is zoom out I'm going to say control dot net if you notice that told me the action that
...right control what was the sdp people
...up what I was doing okay and you can see?
That says something new as appearing not and then if he ever got to use the old smart
tags right this is a replacement for those but a whole lot richer
...I'll bunch richer than it was before instead of just presenting me with the list of
actions here what it's going to do as I move down this list and I'm...maps that you can see it
properly as I move down this list you'll see
...presenting may not just with the action itself but also with
...pretty neat little previewed okay what previous telling me in
...mode you see this green lines for things that are being added
...and red-line some things that are being taken away that's telling me exactly what I'm going to get before I
get so if you're going to...it up,... before hand how you're going to screwed
...better wonderful this is a projection forward into the future
and this comes courtesy of the new roslyn compiler model in the csharp and bb well
god it's offset...know what's going to happen in the future it's kind of a crystal ball if you like right so,
when I hit this thing I'm going to know right away I don't have to go and
hit preview changes to figure out what this thing's going to be for me right so I go ahead and take that change?
And, sure, enough I made...that's cool that's all well and good let's just on do that change
this for a moment that and now I'm a mouse oriented guy just...and I have to...all
...right so, I'm...guide and I want to hover over my
errors and typically what we find is people when...worrying about an error issue they get a hover over the
red squiggles...what better place to parker's?
Lightbulb nice right so,
this is exactly what we put the same experience you can go ahead and that guy up get exactly the same
result previously that light bulb was in my head and most of the time it did show
...that it's a visual studio now right exactly,
yeah, but,...to have the ideas come up...the machete...rely on the brian
...right yeah, so, ...in this new world.
...the light...you might have noticed as I
slid my maps over this guy here on this can zoom in a little bit so you can see it but,
we've got here is a very slight damning if you look at the word...yeah, it's slightly gripe
...subtle and the reason that subtle is we don't...beating your around
...right yet because this is the suggestion right this is just a suggestion so this
one-stop your code compiling this...actually break you completely but it is a suggestion we have
...for how to make it had better okay and what it's going to let me do once again if I put my
...on the line the same cut keyboard experience applies it comes up on the margin...
It tells me I have an unnecessary cast once again I get this handy dandy preview which lets me know what's going
to happen nice,... that I can also apply of any scape that I like...so
whether if I want to eliminate all the unnecessary...in my project I can go ahead and do that and,
that case I will see the...changes dialogue because that's a lot of files to be changing without letting me know what you're doing
...but let's suppose I just want to take this unnecessary cost I can go ahead and
...that's awesome that's really cool but for the next...this I mean you have and reading
...artificially...the next level of
...some right what we've got here is let's introduce that thing again?
Let's make the same mistake twice because I never do that right and,
you'll see that as I types the light...
Right now that should be spurned some thoughts
...if you've ever done this class of thing typically used to come up from static analysis all
...right so you wouldn't find this thing out until...whenever you got rams
...running static analysis right now if you're a good guide that...your build price right ...
maybe it happened on your...build or whatever you'd find out then but if you're like a lot of...find
...maybe weeks like...right and I've accumulated a whole bunch of dead right
...project right you don't want to do that want to find out right now
...the magic here is being enabled by a new feature in roslyn.
Called analyses okay ...feature of the roslyn framework okay they are
and extensible way of expressing rules like the one we just saw a selig
...the references you're adding or how does that work well how that works is these things are typically
their assemblies package this new get packages scott okay and I travel with your project all that
is cool...the app could you make your own custom analyzers and is that what
...absolutely correct...the awesome not only can you write your
I'm okay and I can do ad analyzer okay and I could add a new one I can add one
of the new get packaged my projects habit trouble...my...from a library author let's say I wrote my
and library I can make a set of rules the trouble with that library that's remarkable because now,
... like jim the offers always puts the curly...on the same...man we got fix that
right analyze those a gym...the next slide every time it so that's the kind of
...I know it's a silly example but that's kind of the analyze...do is...at structure code
...what it's doing correct okay so you have full access to the our of the roles and posit and,
you're basically going to be able to figure out when things have gone wrong and
raise the raise issues and not just raise issues mind you...fixes to those issues
and not even when they're wrong but maybe when they're wrong for your organization correct
okay I'm not super important because these things are configured in rule sets right
I have a rules editor here that's actually going to allow me to...so let's go ahead and look
we can find that redundant cast one that I was talking about just there it is and I can decide from
my a policy what shows up
...okay so I could say from my project I never want redundant...and I'm going
to have those...warnings or even is...all wow if I want to do that right so
it's fully in your hands these things trouble with your project is your conventions
your control that's awesome I really like some of these features so let's move on to debugging are
you ready to tell us a little bit out?
Let's see so now that we've now we've analyzed
...code...we've typed in now that we've let the light bulb, come on,
the computers...of our heads once...the thing how can we start to profile these things are look at...
I...so let's turn off I have ...to my screen gets up there
are very excellent so I have do you have up here that's going to make a call to web service
okay and it's going to go ahead and click this button and it's going to go ahead
make just a couple web calls and I can see that that's really not that fast service which that was a lot faster
okay so...old world how I would figure out how to go do
that I'm what I had to probably go try to run some profiler maybe
...some custom instrumentation my code but now what I can do I'm just going-to go down here to
method?
That handles the button click when I click the button on there and as I step
to the code you can see this little tip shows up we call a
...tip here on the approximately how long the code text execute
...awesome stepping from...did nothing to...less than one millisecond to execute so as I go
...can see nothing dressing taping...the...happening step.
And, there's also...between break points as well but so as I step over this one
...I can see...taking a while I know exactly how long it took now
...can see that actually about two seconds to make that web service call dot so now
let's run the methods can make to...there's three things in this list so I'm just going to choose
run to cursor that's like running or break point.
And,...tell me how long it ran from the previous break states
...from a stepper whether to can break points and I can see that
it took about four point to milliseconds to run the additions
...take about two seconds per web service call...a really
...way in the bagger but I can time.
My code about the need to go...stopwatch as a custom instrumentation or run
a profiler outside of course of...so now is your debugging not only, you know,
okay, which code is not doing what I what...although with code is maybe doing what I
want but not really well exactly I don't have to think about ...doing...performance
...just of course debugging I can see along...code text execute that's awesome
okay so there was a question on channel nine but I want to ask about that maybe has a little
bit to do with debugging other end new tools
for game developers in visual studio twenty fifty?
Gathers quite a bit of stuff actually so on day in and,
we have that...multiple levels...the lowest-level we have
...tools for visited graphics and diagnostics so,
people who are using direct text and they want to be able to debugged
profiler applicationswe allow them to do graphics level debugging on those
applications...be able to go and add to a certain pixel and say
...is that pixels that specific color and be able to trace through all the shatters that happen and see, you know,
go all the way into pinpointing where the source of the problem
was right and then we added also now profiling for a for graphics
...debugging also profiling so a bunch of new things happy
...but fifteen in addition to that one of things that we're doing is that we're working with the unity
on having a good support between a visual studio and units of your eyes if you're
creating mobile applications with unityone of the things that we do now is that...small we just had the announced
a partnership with unity a few weeks ago where it's going to be easy to acquire the tool to use both
...in visual studio be easy for you to configure those of the together and also we have
...studio tools for unity and that make it very easy for you to goal
...your csharp code in your favorite environment inside the studio and be able
to the debugging from inside visual studioand, see the app run in the unity editors
it's a very nice combination there that is awesome...your demo sure I feel like there's more we got
a c that's...anymore that we can look at let's do it so next thing I should point out as we were
doing this up performance tip and we're looking at that is this window over here that pops up now
and I start debug instead of new windows I don't think I've seen that yet or brand-new windowed visual
...does fifteen called the diagnostics tools so by default I'm
going-to have memory information about my process so I can...running about thirty nine
megabytes right here so nothing concerning going on right there I can see the cpu consumption of my
...over time to write overtime...so by default zoomed
...kind of my previous breaks...I just went ahead and reset that now
as I scroll back I can see the memory trend
...my entire debug session and maps not really do anything here of
...web coliseum barely using any cpu there's nothing
...worried about their also one of the things we get asked...people really,
really like perth...released is I have the history over here in this debug
events tab that shows the every single step that was recorded I can see
the time that it took so if I want to go back and say I don't remember what my previous
step was I can just look back okay so that first step to two hundred...
seconds about and then when I ran to break point it took about four-point-two seconds so you have a
full history about over there that's awesome well we've incorporated memory tools so I can
take a snapshot I can view all the objects in my keep my process to see if my
see my memory grafting a little bit high I can see what's going on in the always tell us
...I don't think I've ever seen that to this is also knew twenty fifteen being incorporated many bagger
we have...experience of this on top of dump files only the ultimate skewing
...as a okay but the ability to do...debugging and
...a break point is...fifteen and that's an almost use down
to community so this brings up an interesting question because we looked at
some cool stuff and they're used to be a lot of differentiation of which
version of visual studio had what they so of the stuff that you showed can you tell us
all about which things go into which skews?
Sure, everything I've showed so far is available down to the community
...that's a free one right the anyone can use that same for all the stuff I said okay because
I remember watching some of the ultimate stuff like years ago like wow I wish I could have that well,
professional because but this is really need that we're giving these really
powerful tools to anybody...say something I was going to say that one of the things...been asked
...that code...right...for the longest time was only in the high-speed
...view and we brought that down with...
The awesome posits a...completes your id experience all right so here's a
questions coming in...is their...support for...and id avi
the regions I don't know if a dungeons and I thought that's my opinion
righted justify on this is not represent the period by employer I'll give you have
regions you just maybe you should make a new class, you know, I...so in terms of
programming support in the id in general...for reasons it yes we do have support for reasons and
...programming we have a lot of editor program...in
place one of the things that is new invisibility five-fifteen is that refocus on visual studio
sensibility...a one of the things that we're doing now is just make it a lot easier for you as a developer
...customize...environment and...having perhaps...features you want to add
or somethings I want to do for yourself or for your team or you...some scales and you want to create some
open-source project for something that you want to have a customization for everybody and we are creating new tools
in terms of a much better, you know,...some really nice templates
to start from a very good documentation now much... we kind of the not having been investing
in that documentation for a while now it's much reminded frida make extensions new thing
that was it is hard-right but it's good now the nice thing is that also
we're creating this open-source or you know, collection of repositories where we're showing you all
the places where there are people who created open-source extensions you could go on learn from them because one of
the things that we heard from people on...again is that the best source for learning to create
visual studio extensions was going to look at existing thing so whether you look at the
...tools for visual studio or whether looking at other tools they're all good extensions they can go on learn from
so that audio...talking about extensions actually the light bulb that you
...that that's a fully extensible piece to so-if you want-to write your own lightbulb
I already talked about...being one way you can do that but if you're not working and manage languages
in vb and csharp even write your...light bulbs anyways so they were just as well and
other file types as well...just a slightly different way of addressing them so anyone can go posse on those
...awesome all right the jb any cplus-plus improvements visual studio twenty fifty
all many cplus-plus improvements in visit let's hear about the so...probably get the
...guys talk about them...just mention a few
okay and definitely in terms of standardization one of things that's and use that,
you know, continue focus on cplus-plus...fourteen so I know that herb sutter publishes the
...and stuff on low-end and they have you know,
it's lighting up a lot more...cplus-plus levens people's...that's obviously something that's
...twenty fifteen another thing is the focus on multiplies development and
...form so now you can see at targeting android
with cplus-plus and ios as well as you can create and
wineries that or use source...of runs multiple places and now from within business
...you can neck create build and debug android targets...so,
that's...actually one thing...on top of that
...post of on the cplus-plus blog about how because we've added the support for android and we
...debug using gb and now ldap
...on the...how you can use visual studio for general remote targeting of one-x raspberry
pies well-supported wow so it's like now it's a real bigger
house a larger ten more people...stuff they want
...all right go ahead...they on-call choice I showed the...the memory to working for manage
...tool works for native as well so if you're doing cplus-plus you need to
solve memory problems we have the memory to works very similar all
does allocation tracking rather than reference graphs...native so you just of your attached to the
natively bagger you...take snapshot it'll record what state of all the allocations
where that point you...different point take another snapshot and we'll show you all the allocations
...allocated since the first nap...you got what one really cool thing...we're talking about
...buses that in the editor now as we're getting a lot of idea...a
improvements at one of the things that I really like about visit and fifteen is that it has this little feature
...you can synchronize declarations and definitions so you go and...something in the and
the cplus-plus I'll see it and cp file and... synchronize that to header file is just
...and now you're header and I want to see this is a sounds like too much...I have a quick little demo
...even had one going that's awesome is one I prepared earlier.
...really trivial method...couple arguments here.
Okay, so, I get the end of this line and typically what I'm going to want to do at that point.
You see the lightbulb...okay.
The magic...what's happened here, yeah, I actually got my cp file that I want to go...that method
...of inline moi...
...here which is actually a feature that's been around for a while but we've leveraged it together with the
light bulb here to allow you to go ahead and create the body about that
method right away and you do you can texturally as well so you're right in line you have
...the context of the heady or working and you can just go ahead and work and type it in...it
up that's really cool aren't paying that's not only related cplus-plus but also covers
everybody is one of focuses for visual studio this releases that we focused on people creating a
classic...applications and people who are using cloud services in their development
got so, a one of the things that we've added is that we've learned that a lot of people as
they're doing their development they have to deal with multiple accounts, you know, I have this, you know, sequel as
or database that I'm using and I have this feature from visual studio online amusing this thing
...all from outside microsoft completely get...somewhere right...it, you know, constantly as you're using the
id you get prompted to enter username enter your password for this thing for that thing and you
...multiple times the things that we added for resisted five-fifteen it's you know,
single sign on where you basically tell us about all like
...that you have and then we will remember them and then every time you're just using
...connecting to...anything we'll just go through your accounts
authenticate with the right one and you get going so much less typing of
...passwords at...id which isone of my favorite things that we've added this time around got it right so there's
a more questions...gets the questionable python tools for visual studio
be getting the new libel feature in csharp six and visual basic fourteen
...down-arrow the answer to that question but...as I say this extension
...that any language can take so whenever anybody who writes languages ready to
...and provide their own capabilities like that they can do that so but that's actually
happening varying rights across the different languages...they're all possible got next question
will we will we be able to use visual studio for art we
know development that's an interesting question we.
Are we going to be able to users...development I don't think you can do it right now I know that, you know,
we have...team and they're looking at what you can do with visited development targeting
General devices in general including are doing a devices I don't have anything to
...point god I know that we have people looking at that space in general this is going to be a
really fast answer because advanced already are the debugging improvements like diagnostic tools
...the community addition absolutely yes they
are that's great all right another question will other types
of extensions also be supported by new get delivery tool windows etc.
...question I think what they're asking is because if you're talking about extensibility visual studio
...wondering if that they want some kind of repository were all these deliver people could download
the...a new get so you can do it via new get a about what you can do is
...reading revamping the gallery diversity gallery and we're creating new experiences
and which you're going to be able to very easily from within the
id or from within, you know, the browser goal and find you senses be
recommended new expenses and be able to get them to your to your id...directly so that's one thing
we're investing just making the gallery that place where you can go and get
...and easily make them with constantly heard people tell us that they also want those to be able to be
synchronize across all their machines so while we don't do that today we definitely heard that feedbacks oats
an are backlog our next question well visual seo twenty thirteen extensions be supported
in bs twenty fifteen and there have not been at tama changes between
...thirteen and twenty fifteen in terms of breaking changes for extensions
is very easy for an extension developer to go and take the twenty thirteen about extension and
move twenty fifteen we still make it at and now voluntary thing a
...a specific action that you have...have to take to make sure that extension developers goal and
tester extensions with the latest product so that you just not getting something that would crash on
yours right so just to make sure...have a certain level quality platform extension developer perspective
it's very easy to go take their existing twenty thirteen extension and take it to...fifty and where working
action with the top extensions make sure that launch you're going to have that experience...got
...all right next question those bs twenty fifteen have any significant changes in
tf integration overview...thirteen?
You know,
I don't know the answer to that...like for me like look if we have...questions run out I
would totally like look I use visual studio for so long but I bet there's like little nuggets of
gold you can tell me about features that you're surprised we don't know about you tell us there's so much
of visual studio that it's hard to say I know everything about idled
...used it for fifteen years I know that we have a team those dedicated to
working on the integration outsource control in general with visual studio and
...fs is our premier source controls obviously...that...I imagine there have been
...just not the right guide to comment on it john aso their plans...sixty four-bit visual studio.
That's a good one that's always a question that comes up one of the things that we have
...to answer the question if we don't have...but, you know,
visual studio...that there's no sixty four-bit version of...with that said
we do have technologies within visual studio that are actually running...sixty-four
...while you actually have a thirty two-bit...we have internal technology in which
we get some components that we know consume a lot of memory, you know, for example,
I know that like cplus-plus intelligence and probably some of things in debugging where we execute those as
sixty four-bit and we have...thirty but shel interactive...so parts of aches parts of
...are ready running sixty four-bit it's just that like the shelling the editor we
...we don't have that running it's gotthere's an interesting question about the
editor fear and it brings up sort of the notion of is
their extensibility that you can do with the editor the question is
...editor mode in the editor I don't know if you could say well what...be
...it but other ways to do extensions to the ns yes there are ways that you can write
that editor extensions that emulate particular key...and ways of doing things
...a pretty flexible service and very extensible in the way that it works and,
people have written several interesting extensions but doing...different ways of
...bindings that kind of thing is a fairly typical one...do but also changing the way the
...works...more radical...is perfectly possible through extensibility and if
there's an enthusiastic community around something like that than that there's nothing to stop and...and
building and extension...like you mentioned before go ahead and take a look at the extensions that have already been
open resources open that you take a look and see how it works exactly so are right
...will we see any better support for...for templates built into the future visual studio
updates edges syntax highlighting or tell us that seems to be out of the scope of the tool
...more ability for language you have any say about that or just.
I don't know the...there so it's whoever rights t for...and I think the cool thing is that I think I'm learning
here that visual studios is fabulous tool we're going to add what we think you need
...if you need more you can totally do-it-yourself to...right next question will
we see a more efficient implementation of direct symbol referencing
inline assembly wow that's a inline assembly that's pretty.
...pretty
...I don't know I actually know that we're not investing very much in terms of like the editing experience
...assembly so what...inline assembly I've never used one so ...you're writing some
...typically likes of c code and you want to have an implementation of
...something it written down like moi though I like obviously like...the of
the...a sm in the see code on assuming that's what the what is reference
...is...so you don't trust the compiler and you wanted to your online assembly
...that typically tends to be and that person wants immediate performance
boost for the current chip that they are targeting because right typically on people do that, you know, they're obsolete
...a couple of couple years but so I think this is a good question to sort of start wrapping up on
...which we thoughts what features are not available in
communities because it seems like everything we keeps talking about is in communication
...something that's not you can goes into that so you in the diagnostic space we have been
...are historical debugging technology in twenty fifteen that is
...enterprise got so as...
finishing up we got a minute left where can people go to learn more about each of the things you talked about
I will start with you and...will work with... the best place to learn about what's
in the new things and business to do is obviously blog like to me that is the source of new information scummy and
obviously there's also...the and documentation but if...going to learning an about,
you know, the different new things and what is it and what the
...we always...always going to...to blogging you're going to find a block was, for example,
for the...which we just-released we have a blog
...says like here the new things here's what's coming here's how it works and then it references other blog...you can go and
learn from...references...documentation that you can you can see so you'll read their,
for example, something we didn't talk about like now we work on really good high dpi machines and
...looks beautiful they're all right ten seconds each all right so diagnostics
...blog aka dot microsoft last diagnostics blog
...about all the diagnostics features that we're doing there all right and you're up yepsame thing
...hit the bs blog if you want to know about that very specific question about bs offerings is a great page
...visual studio online which will...thatand,
also causal these great sessions that we've been doing it build which...going to be online very shortly...
thanks so much for spending time with us thanks for watching...catch you guys after the break simulator...